<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hangman>
    <Cat att="Myth">
        <Phrase>Aphrodite</Phrase>
        <Hint>Greek: The goddess of love, beauty and desire. Daughter of Zeus.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Apollo</Phrase>
        <Hint>Greek: The god of music, healing, plague, the su, prophecies, and poetry.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Ares</Phrase>
        <Hint>Greek: The god of war, bloodshed, violence, manly courage, and civil order.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Artemis</Phrase>
        <Hint>Greek: Virgin goddess of the hunt, wilderness, animal, young girls, childbirth and plague.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Athena</Phrase>
        <Hint>Greek: The goddess of wisdom, warfare, battle strategy, heroic endeavour, handicrafts and reason.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Demeter</Phrase>
        <Hint>Greek: The goddess of agriculture, horticulture, grain and harvest.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Dionysus</Phrase>
        <Hint>Greek: The god of wine, parties and festivals, madness, chaos, drunkenness and ecstasy.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Hades</Phrase>
        <Hint>Greek: King of the Underworld and god of the dead and the hidden wealth of the Earth.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Hephaestus</Phrase>
        <Hint>Greek: Crippled god of fire, metalworking, stonemasonry, sculpture and volcanism.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Hera</Phrase>
        <Hint>Greek: The queen of the gods and goddess of marriage, women, childbirth, heirs, kings and empires.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Hermes</Phrase>
        <Hint>Greek: The god of travel, messengers, trade, thievery, cunning wiles and language.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Hestia</Phrase>
        <Hint>Greek: Virgin goddess of the hearth, home and cooking.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Poseidon</Phrase>
        <Hint>Greek: The god of the sea, rivers, floods, droughts, earthquakes, and the creator of horses.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Zeus</Phrase>
        <Hint>Greek: The king of the gods, the ruler of Mount Olympus and the god of the sky.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Hathor</Phrase>
        <Hint>Egyptian: Goddess of Happiness.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Bast</Phrase>
        <Hint>Egyptian: The cat-headed Goddess of Fertility, Sensuality and Fire Prevention.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Thoth</Phrase>
        <Hint>Egyptian: Well-known God with the head of an Ibis.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Isis</Phrase>
        <Hint>Egyptian: Goddess of Motherhood, Royalty and Family Commitment.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Anubis</Phrase>
        <Hint>Egyptian: God of the Dead and Lord of Mummy Wrappings.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Ra</Phrase>
        <Hint>Egyptian: The Eye of the Sun.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Osiris</Phrase>
        <Hint>Egyptian: Husband of Isis</Hint>

        <Phrase>Shu</Phrase>
        <Hint>Egyptian: Primeval God of Air, along with his twin sister TEFNUT.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Set</Phrase>
        <Hint>Egyption: God of Chaos.</Hint>	
	
        <Phrase>Jupiter</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: King of Gods</Hint>

        <Phrase>Juno</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: Queen of the Gods</Hint>

        <Phrase>Neptune</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: God of the Sea</Hint>

        <Phrase>Pluto</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: God of Death</Hint>

        <Phrase>Apollo</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: God of the Sun</Hint>

        <Phrase>Diana</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: Goddess of the Moon</Hint>

        <Phrase>Mars</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: God of War</Hint>

        <Phrase>Venus</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: Goddess of Love</Hint>

        <Phrase>Cupid</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: God of Love</Hint>

        <Phrase>Mercury</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: Messenger of the Gods</Hint>

        <Phrase>Minerva</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: Goddess of Wisdom</Hint>

        <Phrase>Ceres</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: The Earth Goddess</Hint>

        <Phrase>Proserpine</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: Goddess of the Underworld</Hint>

        <Phrase>Vulcan</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: The Smith God</Hint>

        <Phrase>Bacchus</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: God of Wine</Hint>

        <Phrase>Saturn</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: God of Time</Hint>

        <Phrase>Vesta</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: Goddess of the Home</Hint>

        <Phrase>Janus</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: God of Doors</Hint>

        <Phrase>Uranus</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: God of the Sky and Father of Saturn</Hint>

        <Phrase>Gaia</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: Goddess of the Earth and Mother of Saturn</Hint>

        <Phrase>Maia</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: Goddess of Growth</Hint>

        <Phrase>Flora</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: Goddess of Flowers</Hint>

        <Phrase>Plutus</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: God of Wealth</Hint>

        <Phrase>Cerberus</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: Dog of the Underworld</Hint>

        <Phrase>Gorgon</Phrase>
        <Hint>Roman: Turns you to stone</Hint>
    </Cat>
    <Cat att="Movies">
        <Phrase>The Shawshank Redemption</Phrase>
        <Hint>Two imprisoned men bond over a number of years, finding solace and eventual redemption through acts of common decency.</Hint>

        <Phrase>The Dark Knight</Phrase>
        <Hint>When Batman, Gordon and Harvey Dent launch an assault on the mob, they let the clown out of the box, the Joker, bent on turning Gotham on itself and bringing any heroes down to his level.</Hint>

        <Phrase>The Lord of the Rings The Return of the King</Phrase>
        <Hint>Aragorn leads the World of Men against Sauron&apos;s army to draw the dark lord&apos;s gaze from Frodo and Sam who are on the doorstep of Mount Doom with the One Ring.</Hint>

        <Phrase>The Lord of the Rings The Fellowship of the Ring</Phrase>
        <Hint>An innocent hobbit of The Shire journeys with eight companions to the fires of Mount Doom to destroy the One Ring and the dark lord Sauron forever.</Hint>

        <Phrase>The Matrix</Phrase>
        <Hint>A computer hacker learns from mysterious rebels about the true nature of his reality and his role in the war against its controllers.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Gladiator</Phrase>
        <Hint>When a Roman general is betrayed and his family murdered by an emperor&apos;s corrupt son, he comes to Rome as a gladiator to seek revenge.</Hint>

        <Phrase>The Lion King</Phrase>
        <Hint>Tricked into thinking he killed his father, a guilt ridden lion cub flees into exile and abandons his identity as the future King.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade</Phrase>
        <Hint>When Dr. Henry Jones Sr. suddenly goes missing while pursuing the Holy Grail, eminent archaeologist Indiana Jones must follow in his father&apos;s footsteps and stop the Nazis.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Batman Begins</Phrase>
        <Hint>Bruce Wayne loses his philanthropic parents to a senseless crime, and years later becomes the Batman to save the crime-ridden Gotham City on the verge of destruction by an ancient order.</Hint>
	
        <Phrase>The Godfather</Phrase>
        <Hint>The aging patriarch of an organized crime dynasty transfers control of his clandestine empire to his reluctant son.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Inception</Phrase>
        <Hint>In a world where technology exists to enter the human mind through dream invasion.</Hint>

        <Phrase>WALL E</Phrase>
        <Hint>In the distant future, a small waste collecting robot inadvertently embarks on a space journey that will ultimately decide the fate of mankind.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Braveheart</Phrase>
        <Hint>William Wallace, a commoner, unites the 13th Century Scots in their battle to overthrow English rule.</Hint>
        
        <Phrase>Pulp Fiction</Phrase>
        <Hint>The lives of two mob hit men, a boxer, a gangster&apos;s wife, and a pair of diner bandits intertwine in four tales of violence and redemption.</Hint>

    </Cat>
    <Cat att="Series">
        <Phrase>Game of Thrones</Phrase>
        <Hint>Seven noble families fight for control of the mythical land of Westeros.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Breaking Bad</Phrase>
        <Hint>Informed he has terminal cancer, an underachieving chemistry genius turned high school teacher uses his expertise to secretly provide for his family by producing the world&apos;s highest quality crystal meth.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Arrested Development</Phrase>
        <Hint>Level-headed son Michael Bluth takes over family affairs after his father is imprisoned. But the rest of his spoiled, dysfunctional family are making his job unbearable.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Sherlock</Phrase>
        <Hint>A modern update finds the famous sleuth and his doctor partner solving crime in 21st century London.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Dexter</Phrase>
        <Hint>A likeable Miami police forensics expert moonlights as a serial killer of criminals who he believes have escaped justice.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Avatar The Last Airbender</Phrase>
        <Hint>In a war-torn world of elemental magic, a young boy reawakens to undertake a dangerous mystic quest to fulfill his destiny as the Avatar.</Hint>

        <Phrase>The Legend of Korra</Phrase>
        <Hint>Avatar Korra must defend the neutral Republic City from the Equalists, a massive secret society with the purpose of ridding the entire world of the ability to manipulate the elements of nature.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Death Note</Phrase>
        <Hint>An intelligent high school student goes on a secret crusade to eliminate criminals from the world after discovering a notebook capable of killing anyone whose name is written into it.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Suits</Phrase>
        <Hint>On the run from a drug deal gone bad, Mike Ross, a brilliant college-dropout, finds himself a job working with Harvey Specter, one of New York City&apos;s best lawyers.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Castle</Phrase>
        <Hint>After a serial killer imitates the plots of his novels, successful mystery novelist Richard &quot;Rick&quot;   Castle gets permission from the Mayor of New York City to tag along with an NYPD homicide investigation team for research purposes.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Stargate SG1</Phrase>
        <Hint>A secret military team, SG-1, is formed to explore the recently discovered StarGates.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Stargate Atlantis</Phrase>
        <Hint>An international team of scientists and military personnel discover a Stargate network in the Pegasus Galaxy and come face-to-face with a new, powerful enemy, The Wraith.</Hint>

        <Phrase>Stargate Universe</Phrase>
        <Hint>Trapped on an Ancient spaceship billions of light years from home, a group of soldiers and civilians struggle to survive and find their way back to Earth.</Hint>
		
        <Phrase>Supernatural</Phrase>
        <Hint>Two brothers follow their father's footsteps as "hunters" fighting evil beings of many kinds including monsters, demons, and gods that roam the earth. </Hint>
    
        <Phrase>Community</Phrase>
        <Hint>A smarmy lawyer, whose education is deemed void by the bar, is forced to attend a local community college with an extremely eclectic staff and student body. </Hint>
		
        <Phrase>The Walking Dead</Phrase>
        <Hint>Police officer Rick Grimes leads a group of survivors in a world overrun by zombies. </Hint>
    </Cat>
    <Cat att="Cars">
        <Phrase>Chevrolet Corvette</Phrase>
        <Hint>American First released in 1953 Named after a small military ship</Hint>

        <Phrase>Chevrolet Camaro</Phrase>
        <Hint>American First released in 1967 Bumblebees' disguise in the transformers movies</Hint>
		
		<Phrase>Chevrolet Corvette String Ray Coupe</Phrase>
		<Hint>American Released in 1963 Split rear window. Produced for 20 years</Hint>

		<Phrase>Ford GT40</Phrase>
		<Hint>American Built to compete with Ferrari. Only American built to ever take Le Mans overall.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Aston Martin DB5</Phrase>
		<Hint>Bond made it famous in Goldfinger Built from 1963-1965 and boasted a then-healthy 282 horsepower</Hint>

		<Phrase>AC Shelby Cobra 427</Phrase>
		<Hint>Did the quarter-mile in 13.2 seconds and handled like it was on rails. Runs on a 520 bhp 427 V8 Ford engine.</Hint>

		<Phrase>DeLorean DMC 12</Phrase>
		<Hint>Stainless steel body, gullwing doors and a body flat enough to grill on.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Jaguar E Type</Phrase>
		<Hint>Burbling V12 power and ridiculously low slung body</Hint>

		<Phrase>1967 Pontiac GTO</Phrase>
		<Hint>Otherwise known as the “Judge”. Split grille design and the monster 335 hp, 441 lb ft V8 engine,along with the optional Hurst shifter .</Hint>

		<Phrase>Nissan Skyline GTR r34</Phrase>
		<Hint>Its origins date back to 1989 with what was dubbed “Godzilla” by the automotive press.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Rolls Royce Phantom</Phrase>
		<Hint>The original British luxury car that started its run in 1925.</Hint>

		<Phrase>McLaren F1</Phrase>
		<Hint>In 1998, engineer Gordon Murray set the world on fire by setting a new production car top speed record of 231 mph in this car. </Hint>

		<Phrase>Bugatti Veyron</Phrase>
		<Hint>Released in 2005, the 8-liter W16, quad turbo,1001 horsepower engine launched the original to a top speed of 253 mph.</Hint>
    </Cat>
    <Cat att="Drinks">
        <Phrase>Coffee</Phrase>
        <Hint>Made from grounded beans.</Hint>
		
		<Phrase>Margarita</Phrase>
		<Hint>Cocktail: Mixture of Lime Juice, Triple Sec and Tequila</Hint>

		<Phrase>Mai Tai</Phrase>
		<Hint>Cocktail: Mixture of Dark Rum, Orange Curacao, Lime Juice and Almond Syrup</Hint>

		<Phrase>White Russian</Phrase>
		<Hint>Cocktail: Mixture of Fresh Cream, Kahlua and Vodka</Hint>

		<Phrase>Caipirinha</Phrase>
		<Hint>Cocktail: Five lime segments in Cachca</Hint>

		<Phrase>Screwdriver</Phrase>
		<Hint>Coctail: Mixture of Orange Juice and Vodka</Hint>

		<Phrase>Bloody Mary</Phrase>
		<Hint>Cocktail: Mixture of Tomato Juice and Vodka</Hint>

		<Phrase>Whiskey Sour</Phrase>
		<Hint>Cocktail: Mixture of Bourbon and Lime Juice</Hint>

		<Phrase>Old Fashioned</Phrase>
		<Hint>Cocktail: Mixture of Bourbon and Water</Hint>

		<Phrase>Manhattan</Phrase>
		<Hint>Cocktail: Mixture of Italian Sweet Vermouth and Bourbon</Hint>

		<Phrase>Martini</Phrase>
		<Hint>Cocktail: Mixture of French Dry Vermouth and Gin</Hint>

		<Phrase>Daiquiri</Phrase>
		<Hint>Cocktail: Mixture of Lime Juice and White Rum</Hint>

		<Phrase>Cosmopolitan</Phrase>
		<Hint>Cocktail: Mixture of Lime Juice, Pink Grapefruit Juice, Cranberry Juice, Cointreau and Vodka</Hint>

		<Phrase>Singapore Sling</Phrase>
		<Hint>Cocktail: Mixture of Soda, Cherry Brandy, Lemon Juice, Sloe Gin and Gin</Hint>

		<Phrase>Mojito</Phrase>
		<Hint>Cocktail: Mixture of Lime Juice and Rum with mint leaves</Hint>

		<Phrase>Mint Julep</Phrase>
		<Hint>Cocktail: Mixture of Water and Bourbon with mint leaves</Hint>

		<Phrase>Tom Collins</Phrase>
		<Hint>Cocktail: Mixture of Soda, Gin and Lemon Juice</Hint>

		<Phrase>Pina Colada</Phrase>
		<Hint>Cocktail: Mixture of Pineapple Juice, White Rum and Coconut Cream</Hint>

		<Phrase>Sea Breeze</Phrase>
		<Hint>Cocktail: Mixture of Grapefruit Juice, Cranberry Juice and Vodka</Hint>

		<Phrase>Cuba Libre</Phrase>
		<Hint>Cocktail: Mixture of Cola, Lime Juice and White Rum</Hint>

		<Phrase>Bellini</Phrase>
		<Hint>Cocktail: Mixture of Peach Puree and Prosecco</Hint>
    </Cat>
    <Cat att="Sport">
        <Phrase>Squash</Phrase>
        <Hint>2 Player game, played by hitting a small rubber ball against a wall</Hint>
		
		<Phrase>Rugby</Phrase>
		<Hint>Team sport. 15 players in a team. Played with a oval shaped ball</Hint>

		<Phrase>Soccer</Phrase>
		<Hint>Team sport. 11 players on a team. Player need to kick a round ball into a net to score.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Cricket</Phrase>
		<Hint>Team sport. Bat-and-ball game played between two teams of 11 players on a field, at the centre of which is a rectangular 22-yard long pitch.</Hint>
		
		<Phrase>Snowboarding</Phrase>
		<Hint>A winter sport that involves descending a slope that is covered with snow while standing on a board attached to a rider&apos;s feet.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Surfing</Phrase>
		<Hint>A surface water sport in which the wave rider rides on the forward face of a wave.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Target Archery</Phrase>
		<Hint>Shooting arrows at a target for accuracy from a set distance or distances.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Volleyball</Phrase>
		<Hint>A team sport in which two teams of 6 players are separated by a net. Each team tries to score points by grounding a ball on the other team&apos;s court under organized rules.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Basketball</Phrase>
		<Hint>A team sport, the objective being to shoot a ball through a basket horizontally positioned to score points. Usually, two teams of 5 players play on a marked rectangular court with a basket at each width end.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Skateboarding</Phrase>
		<Hint>An action sport which involves riding and performing tricks on a specially designed maplewood board combined with a polyurethane coating used for making smoother slides and stronger durability.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Martial Arts</Phrase>
		<Hint>Use codified systems and traditions of combat practices. They are practiced for a variety of reasons, including self-defense, competition, physical health and fitness, as well as mental, physical, and spiritual development.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Fencing</Phrase>
		<Hint>An activity using bladed weapons. This sport is divided into three weapons: Foil, Sabre and Epee.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Boxing</Phrase>
		<Hint>A combat sport in which two people engage in a contest of strength, reflexes, and endurance by throwing punches at an opponent with gloved hands.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Gymnastics</Phrase>
		<Hint>A sport involving the performance of exercises requiring physical strength, flexibility, agility, coordination, and balance. </Hint>

		<Phrase>Formula Racing</Phrase>
		<Hint>A motorsport involving the racing of cars for competition.</Hint>
    </Cat>
    <Cat att="Games">
        <Phrase>Monopoly</Phrase>
        <Hint>Board Game: Making money and managing properties.</Hint>
	
        <Phrase>Twister</Phrase>
        <Hint>Physical Game: Played on a large plastic mat that is spread on the floor or ground. The mat has four rows of large colored circles on it with a different color in each row</Hint>
		
		<Phrase>Battleship</Phrase>
		<Hint>Board Game: You must guess coordinates and sink your opponent's vessels</Hint>
		
		<Phrase>Jenga</Phrase>
		<Hint>Players take turns to remove a block from a tower and balance it on top, creating a taller and increasingly unstable structure as the game progresses.</Hint>
		
		<Phrase>Beer Pong</Phrase>
		<Hint>Drinking game in which players throw a ping pong ball across a table with the intent of landing the ball in a cup of beer on the other end.</Hint>
		
		<Phrase>Hungry Hungry Hippos</Phrase>
		<Hint>The purpose of the game is for each player to collect as many marbles as possible with his or her 'hippo' (a toy hippo model).</Hint>
		
		<Phrase>Snakes and Ladders</Phrase>
		<Hint>A number of "ladders" and "snakes" (or "chutes") are pictured on the board, each connecting two specific board squares.</Hint>
		
		<Phrase>Chutes and Ladders</Phrase>
		<Hint>A number of "ladders" and "snakes" (or "chutes") are pictured on the board, each connecting two specific board squares.</Hint>
		
		<Phrase>Backgammon</Phrase>
		<Hint>The playing pieces are moved according to the roll of dice, and players win by removing all of their pieces from the board. </Hint>
		
		<Phrase>Game of the Generals</Phrase>
		<Hint>The game simulates armies at war trying to outflank and outmaneuver each other. As in actual warfare, the game allows only one side's plan to succeed.</Hint>
		
		<Phrase>Mastermind</Phrase>
		<Hint>One player becomes the codemaker, the other the codebreaker. The codemaker chooses a pattern of four code pegs. Duplicates are allowed, so the player could even choose four code pegs of the same color. The chosen pattern is placed in the four holes covered by the shield, visible to the codemaker but not to the codebreaker.</Hint>
		
		<Phrase>ClueDo</Phrase>
		<Hint>The object of the game is for players to strategically move around the game board (a mansion), in the guise of one of the game's six characters, collecting clues from which to deduce which suspect murdered the game's perpetual victim, Mr. X (Mr. Boddy in North American versions), and with which weapon and in what room.</Hint>		
    </Cat>
    <Cat att="Actors">
        <Phrase>Richard Dean Anderson</Phrase>
        <Hint>Known for his role as MacGyver and in Stargate</Hint>
        
        <Phrase>Jared Padalecki</Phrase>
        <Hint>Known for his role in Supernatural as Sam Winchester</Hint>
    
        <Phrase>Jensen Ackles</Phrase>
        <Hint>Known for his role in Supernatural as Dean Winchester</Hint>
		
		<Phrase>Mike Myers</Phrase>
		<Hint>Known for his roles in Auston Powers, Wayne's World and Shrek</Hint>
		
		<Phrase>Molly Quinn</Phrase>
		<Hint>Known for her role in Castle as Alexis</Hint>
		
		<Phrase>Nathan Fillion</Phrase>
		<Hint>Known for his role as Richard Castle in Castle</Hint>
			
		<Phrases>Michael Hall</Phrases>
		<Hint>Known for his role in Dexter</Hint>
			
		<Phrase>Emily Deschanel</Phrase>
		<Hint>Known for her role as Dr. Temperance in Bones</Hint>
			
		<Phrase>David Boreanaz</Phrase>
		<Hint>Known for his role as Special Agent Seeley Booth in Bones</Hint>
    </Cat>
    <Cat att="People">
        <Phrase>Adolf Hitler</Phrase>
        <Hint>Famous for being fascist Dictator of Germany  Born - 20th April 1889, Braunau am Inn, Austria Died - 30th April 1945, Berlin, Germany committed suicide</Hint>

        <Phrase>Anne Frank</Phrase>
        <Hint>Famous for writing a diary about her holocaust experience Born - 12th June 1929 Died - March 1945 in Bergen-Belsen from typhus</Hint>

        <Phrase>Christopher Columbus</Phrase>
        <Hint>Famous for being an explorer and first European to set foot in the Americas Born - c. 1451 exact date unknown Died - 20th May 1506, Valladolid, Castile</Hint>

        <Phrase>Edward the Confessor</Phrase>
        <Hint>Famous for being King of England 1042-1066 Born - c1003 exact date unknown Died - 5th January 1066</Hint>

        <Phrase>Galileo Galilei</Phrase>
        <Hint>Famous for being influential in the development of Science, Astronomy and Mathematics Born - 15th February 1564, Pisa, Italy Died - 8th January 1642</Hint>

        <Phrase>Ivan the Terrible</Phrase>
        <Hint>Famous for being the first Tsar of Russia Born - 25th August 1530 - Kolomenskoye, nr Moscow, Russia Died - 18th March 1584</Hint>

        <Phrase>Julius Caesar</Phrase>
        <Hint>Famous for being Roman Emperor Born - 13th July 100BC Died - 15th March AD 44 assassinated</Hint>

        <Phrase>Napoleon Bonaparte</Phrase>
        <Hint>Famous for being a Emperor of France Born - 15th August 1769,  Ajaccio, Corsica Died - 5th May 1821 St Helena aged 51 probably from stomach cancer</Hint>

        <Phrase>Nelson Mandela</Phrase>
        <Hint>Famous for being leader of the ANC, President of South Africa Born - 18th July 1918, Mvezo, South Africa</Hint>

        <Phrase>Winston Churchill</Phrase>
        <Hint>Famous for being British Prime Minister and World War Two war leader Born - 30th November 1874, Blenheim, Oxfordshire Died - 24th January 1965, London</Hint>

		<Phrase>Abraham Lincoln</Phrase>
		<Hint>In his famous Gettysburg speech, he inspired the nation with his noble words and helped to bring about the abolishment of slavery.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Benjamin Franklin</Phrase>
		<Hint>Great polymath and promoter of American ideals at home and in the US. A practical man of great dynamism and good character.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Albert Einstein</Phrase>
		<Hint>His theories of relativity were a very significant scientific breakthrough. As well as being a genius scientist, he was also a champion of human rights and campaigned for a more peaceful world.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Thomas Jefferson</Phrase>
		<Hint>One of America's founding fathers, he helped draft the Declaration of Independence and foster a belief in human rights. Amongst other achievements, he passed one of the first bills on religious tolerance in his state of Virginia.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Martin Luther King</Phrase>
		<Hint>Inspiring leader of the non-violent civil rights movement. Inspired millions of people black and white to aspire for a more equal society.</Hint>

		<Phrase>William Shakespeare</Phrase>
		<Hint>His plays and poetry captured the richness and diversity of human existence in the most powerful and poetic way.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Leonardo da Vinci</Phrase>
		<Hint>He helped make great advances in anatomy, astronomy, physics, science and others. He also painted the most iconic picture in history - The Mona Lisa.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Muhammad Ali</Phrase>
		<Hint>Champion boxer and great character. Refused to fight in Vietnam war and became a champion of civil rights and African interests.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Mahatma Gandhi</Phrase>
		<Hint>Principle figurehead of the Indian independence movement. Taught a philosophy of non-violence and peaceful protest.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Confucius</Phrase>
		<Hint>Influential Chinese philosopher who laid ground work for much of Chinese philosophy and society.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Louis Pasteur</Phrase>
		<Hint>French scientist who found many important improvements in medical science, e.g. vaccination for Rabies and a safe way to pasteurise milk.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Charles Darwin</Phrase>
		<Hint>Published his Origin of Species detailing a belief in evolution at a time when such a decision was very controversial.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Barack Obama</Phrase>
		<Hint>America's first black president. Offered a positive message of hope to America and world.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Martin Luther</Phrase>
		<Hint>He challenged the excesses of the Catholic church leading to the protestant movement and forcing the Catholic Church to reinvigorate itself.</Hint>
		
		<Phrase>Sir Isaac Newton</Phrase>
		<Hint>One of the greatest scientists of all time. He led the foundation of modern physics with his development of theories on gravity and mechanics</Hint>

		<Phrase>John Lennon</Phrase>
		<Hint>Iconic singer song writer. Member of the Beatles.</Hint>

		<Phrase>Desmond Tutu</Phrase>
		<Hint>South African anti-apartheid campaigner. Sought to heal wounds after end of apartheid through Truth and Reconcilliation committee.</Hint>
		
		<Phrase>Beethoven</Phrase>
		<Hint>Great Classical Composer</Hint>
    </Cat>
</hangman>